Guide to the Lake County Federation of Women's Clubs Records 1936-1985
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Lake County Federation of Women's Clubs Records
1936-1985
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana--Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 203
Lake County Federation of Women's Clubs
0.5 linear feet
The Lake County Federation of Women's Clubs was a confederation of area clubs established in 1925 in Lake County, Montana. The collection consists of the meeting minutes, financial records, certificates, and an artifact.
Historical Note
The Lake County Federation of Women's Clubs, organized in 1925, worked to promote other women's clubs in Lake County, Montana, by joining them together as one organization, while allowing the individual clubs to grow and prosper for themselves. The federation established committees to address such topics as safety, special education, legislation, literature, and Special Olympics. They played an active role in World War II issues, supporting defense bonds, the Red Cross, and the movement to save tin, aluminum, and lard for the war effort. The federation displayed political voice on many subjects ranging from criminal cases to women's suffrage. The federation made a considerable effort to unite women's clubs and operate together for the good of the communities they represented.
The collection consists of the meeting minutes, financial records, and certificates that document the activities and interests of the organization. A gavel used in the meetings is also present in the collection.
The collection is divided into four series:
Series I: Certificates, 1 folder, 1976, 1986
Series II: Financial Records, 3 folders, 1939-1985
Series III: Minutes, 1 minute book and 1 folder, 1936-1985
Series IV: Artifacts, undated
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
These materials were collected and/or created by Betty Brill, last president of the Lake County Federation of Women's Clubs, and held in her possession until donation to the K. Ross Toole Archives.
Gift of Betty Brill, 1987
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Women--Montana--Lake County--Societies and clubs
Montana; Artifacts; City and Town Life; Women
- Certificates, 1976-1983; Series I; 1 folder
  The two certificates in the series are a charter member of the Fort Connah Restoration Society in 1976 and a certificate of appreciation for participation in the Ronan Special Olympics in 1983.
  - Certificates, 1976-1983 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Financial Records, 1939-1985; Series II; 3 folders
  This series consists of a bank statement and a checkbook from the 1980 to the federation's end in 1985. The series also contains a ledger book held by the Treasurer of the federation from 1939 to 1985. It stores all the expenses and credits for the club. The series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Bank Statement, 1984 (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Checkbook, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Treasurer's Book, 1939-1985 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Minutes, 1936-1985; Series III; 1 minute book and 1 folder
  The series consists of an October 6, 1984 meeting agenda and a minute book of the meetings from October 1, 1936 to April 25, 1985. This book tells of the activities and interests of the federation, and it lists in order the presidents of the federation in the beginning of the book. The series is arranged alphabetically.
  - Agenda, 1984 (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Minutes Book, 1936-1985 (Box-folder 1/6)
- Artifacts, Series IV
  This series consists of a gavel that was presented to the federation by the St. Ignatius Women's Club.
  - Gavel, 203(IV):1 (Box-folder 1/7)